Wonder by RJ palao aftermath MOM WAS WAITING for me in
front of the school along with all the other parents when the bus arrived. Mr.
Tushman told me on the bus ride home that they had called my parents to tell
them there had been a “situation” the night before but that everyone was fine.
He said the camp director and several of the counselors went looking for the
hearing aid in the morning while we all went swimming in the lake, but they
couldn’t find it anywhere Roar wood would reimburse us the cost of the
hearing aid he said. They felt bad about what happened. I wondered if Eddie had
taken my hearing aids with him as kind of a souvenir. Something to remember the
workc Mom gave me a tight hug when I got
off the bus, but she didn’t slam me with questions like I thought she might. Her
hug felt good, and I didn’t shake it off like some of the other kids were doing
with their parents’' hugs.
The bus driver started unloading our duffel bags, and I went to find mine
while Mom talked to Mr. Tushman and Miss Ruben who had walked over to her. As I
rolled my bag toward her, a lot of kids who don’t usually say anything to me
were nodding hello, or patting my back as I walked by them. “Ready?” Mom said when she
saw me. She took my duffel bag, and I
didn’t even try to hold on to it: I was
fine with her carrying it. If she had wanted to carry me on her shoulders, I
would have been fine with that, too, to be truthful. As we started to walk away, Mr.
Tushman gave me a quick, tight hug but didn’t say
anything home MOM AND I didn’t talk much the whole walk home, and when we got to
the front stoop, I automatically looked in the front bay window, because I forgot
for a second that Daisy wasn’t going to be there like always, perched on the sofa
with her front paws on the window seal waiting for us to come home made me kind
of sad when we walked inside. As soon as we did, Mom dropped my duffel bag and
wrapped her arms around me and kissed me on my head and on my face like she was
breathing me in. “It’s okay, Mom, I’m fine,” I
said, smiling. She nodded and took my face in her hands. Her eyes were shiny. “I know
you are,” she said. “I missed you so much Augie I missed you, too.” I could tell she
wanted to say a lot of things but she was stopping herself. “Are you hungry?” she asked.
“Starving. Can I have a grilled cheese?” “Of course,” she answered, and immediately
started to make the sandwich while I took my jacket off and sat down at the
kitchen counter. “Where’s Via?” I asked.
“She’s coming home with Dad today. Boy, did she miss you, Auggie,” Mom said. “Yeah you
would have liked the nature reserve. You know what movie they played? The Sound of
Music “You’ll have to tell her that.” “So, do
you want to hear about the bad part or the good part first?” I asked after a few
minutes, leaning my head on my hand.
“Whatever you want to talk about,” she answered. “Well, except for last night, I
had an awesome time,” I said. “I mean, it was
just awesome. That’s why I’m so bummed. I feel like they ruined the whole trip for
me.” “No, sweetie, don’t let them do that to you. You were there for more than 48
hours, and that awful part lasted 1 hour.
Don’t let them take that away from you, okay?” “I know.” I nodded. “Did Mr. Tushman tell
you about the hearing aids?” “Yes, he called us this morning.” “Was Dad mad? Because they’re so
expensive?” “Oh my gosh, of course not, Auggie. He just wanted to know that you
were all right. That’s all that matters to us. And that you don’t let those thugs
ruin your trip.” I kind of laughed at the way she said the word
“thugs.” “What?” she said Thugs I teased her.
“That’s kind of an old-fashioned word.” “Okay, jerks. Morons imbecile she said,
flipping over the sandwich and the pan.
Cretinos as my mother would have said.
Whatever you want to call them, if I saw them on the street, I would She shook her
head. “They were pretty big, Mom.” I smiled.
“Seventh graders, I think.” She shook her head. “Seventh graders? Mr. Tushman didn’t
tell us that. Oh my goodness.” “Did he tell
you how Jack stood up for me?” I said. “And Amos was like, bam, he rammed right into
the leader. They both crashed to the ground, like in a real fight! It was
pretty awesome. Amos’s lip was bleeding and everything.” “He told us there was a
fight, but she said, looking at me with her eyebrows
raised. “I’m just phew I’m so grateful you
and Amos and Jack are fine. When I think about what could have happened she
trailed off, flipping the grilled cheese again. “My mon hoodie got totally shredded.”
“Well, that can be replaced,” she answered.
She lifted the grilled cheese onto a plate and put the plate in front of me
on the counter. “Milk or white grape juice?” “Chocolate milk, please?” I said devouring
the sandwich. “Oh, can you do it that special way you make it, with the
froth?” “How did you and Jack end up at the
edge of the woods in the first place?” she said, pouring the milk into a tall glass.
“Jack had to go to the bathroom,” I answered, my mouth full. As I was talking,
she spooned in the chocolate powder and started rolling a small whisk between
her palms really fast. “But there was a huge line and he didn’t want to wait. So
we went towards the woods to pee.” She looked up at me while she was whisking. I
know she was thinking we shouldn’t have done that. The chocolate milk in the
glass now had a 2-in froth on top. “That looks good, Mom. Thanks.” “And then what
happened?” she said said, putting the glass in front of
me. I took a long drink of the chocolate
milk. “Is it okay if we don’t talk about it anymore right now?” “Oh. Okay.” “I promise
I’ll tell you all about it later, when
Dad and Via come home. I’ll tell you all
every detail. I just don’t want to have to tell the whole story over and over,
you know?” “Absolutely.” I finished my sandwich in two more bites and gulped down the chocolate
milk. “Wow, you practically inhaled that sandwich. Do you want another one?” she
said. I shook my head and wiped my mouth
with the back of my hand. “Mom? Am I always going to have to worry about jerks like
that?” I asked. “Like when I grow up, is it
always going to be like this?” She didn’t answer right away, but took my plate and
glass and put them in the sink and rinse them with water. “There are always going
to be jerks in the world, Auggie,” she said, looking at me. “But I really believe, and
Daddy really believes, that there are more good people on this earth than bad
people, and the good ones watch out for each other and take care of each other.
Just like Jack was there for you. And Amos. And those other kids.” “Oh yeah, Miles
and Henry,” I answered. “They were awesome, too. It’s weird because Miles and Henry
haven’t even really been very nice to me all during the year.”
“Sometimes people surprise us,” she said, rubbing the top of my head. “I guess.” “Want
another glass of chocolate milk?” “No, I’m good,” I said. “Thanks, Mom. Actually, I’m kind
of tired. I didn’t sleep too good last night.” “You should take a nap. Thanks for
leaving me Baboo, by the way.” “You got my note?” She smiled. “I slept with him both
nights.” She was about to say something else when her cell phone ran and she
answered. She started beaming as she listened. “Oh my goodness, really? What kind?”
she said excitedly. “Yep, he’s right here.
He was about to take a nap. Want to say
hi? Oh, okay, see you in 2 minutes.” She clicked it off. “That was Daddy,” she said
excitedly. “He and Via are just down the block.” “He’s not at work?” I
said there WE CALLED THE puppy Bear because when Mom first saw him, she said
he looked just like a little bear cub. I said: “That’s what we should call him!” and
everyone agreed that that was the perfect name. I took the next day off
from school— —not because my elbow was hurting me, which it was, but so I could
play with Bear all day long. Mom let Via stay home from school, too, so the two of
us took turns cuddling with Bear and playing tug of war with him. We had kept
all of Daisy’s old toys, and we brought
them out now, to see which ones he’d like
best. It was fun hanging out with Via all
day, just the two of us. It was like old times, like before I started going back
to school. Back then, I couldn’t wait for her to come home from school so she
could play with me before starting her homework. Now that we’re older, though, and
I’m going to school and have friends of
my own that I hang out with, we never do that anymore it was nice hanging out
with her laugh laughing and playing. I think she liked it,
too the shift WHEN I WENT back to school the next day, the first thing I noticed
was that there was a big shift in the way things were. A monumental shift. A
seismic shift. Maybe even a cosmic shift.
Whatever you want to call it, it was a big shift. Everyone— —not just in our grade
but every grade— —had heard about what had happened to us with the seventh grade
Traders so suddenly I wasn’t known for what I’d always been known for, but for
this other thing that had happened. And the story of what happened had gotten
bigger and bigger each time it was told.
Two days ago the way the story went was that Amos had gotten into a major fist
fight with the kid, and Miles and Henry and Jack had thrown some punches at the
other guys, too in the escape across the field became this whole long adventure
through a cornfield maze and into the deep dark woods.
Jack’s version of the story was probably the best because he’s so funny, but in
whatever version of the story no matter who was telling it, two things always
stayed the same: I got picked on because of my face and Jack defended me, and
those guys— —Amos, Henry, and Miles— —protected me. And now that they’d protect
me, I was different to them. It was like I
was one of them. They all call me “little dude” now— —even the jocks those big dudes
I barely even knew before would knuckle punch me in the hallways now. Another
thing to come out of it was that Amos became super popular and Julian, because
he missed the whole thing, was really out of the loop. Miles and Henry were hanging
out with Amos all the time now, like they switched best friends. I’d like to be
able to say that Julian started treating me better, too, but that wouldn’t be true.
He still gave me dirty looks across the room. He still never talked to me or Jack.
But he was the only one who was like that now. And me and Jack, we couldn’t
care less Ducks THE DAY BEFORE the last day of school, Mr. Tushman called me into his
office to tell me they had found out the names of the seventh graders from the
nature retreat. He read me off a bunch of names that didn’t mean anything to me,
and then he said the last name: “Edward Johnson.” I nodded. “You recognize the name?”
he said. “They called him Eddie.” “Right. Well, they found this in Edward’s locker.” He
handed me what was left of my hearing aid headband. The right piece was
completely gone and the left one was mangled. The band that connected the two,
the Lobot part, was bent down the middle.
“His school wants to know if you want to press charges,” said Mr.
Tushman. I looked at my hearing a No, I don’t think so.” I shrugged. “I’m being
fitted for new anyway H Why don’t you talk about it
with your parents tonight? I’ll call your mom tomorrow to talk about it with her,
too.” “Would they go to jail?” I asked. “No, not jail. But they’d probably go to juvie
court. And maybe they’ll learn a lesson that way.” “Trust me: that Eddy kid is not
learning any lessons,” I joked. He sat down behind his desk. “Auggie, why don’t you sit
down a second?” he said. I sat down. All the
things on his desk were the same as when I first walked into his office last
summer: the same mirror cube, the same little globe floating in the air. That
felt like ages ago. “Hard to believe this year’s almost over, huh?” he said, almost
like he was reading my mind. “Yeah.” “Has it been a good year for you Augie Has it
been okay?” “Yeah, it’s been good.” I nodded. “I know academically it’s been a great year
for you. You’re one of our top students.
Congrats on the High Honor role Thanks.
Yeah, that’s cool.” “But I know it’s had its share of
ups and downs,” he said, raising his eyebrows. “Certainly, that night at the
nature reserve was one of the low points.” “Yeah.” I nodded. “But it was also
kind of good, too.” “In what way?” “Well, you know, how people stood up for me and
stuff?” “That was pretty wonderful,” he said, smiling. “Yeah.” “I know in school things got
a little hairy with Julian at times.” I have to admit: he surprised me with that
one. “You know about that stuff?” I asked him Middle School directors have a way
of knowing about a lot of stuff.” “Do you have, like, secret security cameras in the
hallways?” I joked. “And microphones everywhere,” he laughed. “No, seriously?” He
laughed again. “No, not seriously.” “Oh!” “But teachers know more than
kids think, Auggie. I wish you and Jack had come to me about the mean notes that
were left in your lockers.” “How do you know about that?” I said. “I’m telling you
Middle School directors know all “It wasn’t that big a deal,” I am
answered. “And we wrote notes, too.” He smiled. “I don’t know if it’s public yet,”
he said, “though it will be soon anyway, but Julian albins is not coming back to
beat your Prep next year.” “What!” I said. I honestly couldn’t hide how surprised I
was. “His parents don’t think beat your Prep is a good fit for him,” Mr. Tushman
continued, raising his shoulders. “Wow, that’s big news,” I said.
“Yeah, I thought you should know.” Then suddenly I noticed that the pumpkin portrait that
used to be behind his desk was gone in my drawing, my Self-Portrait as an Animal
that I drew for the New Year Art Show, was now framed and hanging behind his
desk. “Hey, that’s mine!” I pointed. Mr.
Tushman turned around like he didn’t know what I was talking about. “Oh, that’s
right!” he said, tapping his forehead. “I’ve been meaning to show this to you for
months now.” “My- portrait as a duck.” I nodded. “I love this piece, Auggie,” he said.
“When your art teacher showed it to me, I
asked her if I could keep it for my wall.
I hope that’s okay with you.” “Oh, yeah! Sure.
What happened to the pumpkin portrait?” “Right behind you.” “Oh, yeah. Nice.” “I’ve been
meaning to ask you since I hung this up he said, looking at it. “Why did you choose
used to represent yourself as a duck?” “What do you mean?” I answered. “That was the
assignment.” “Yes, but why a duck?” he said. “Is it safe to assume that it was because of
the story of the um, the duckling that turns into a swan?” “No,” I laughed, shaking
my head. “It’s because I think I look like a duck.” “Oh!” said Mr. Tushman, his eyes
opening wide. He started laughing. “Really?
Huh. Here I was looking for symbolism and metaphors and, um sometimes a duck is
just a duck!” “Yeah, I guess,” I said, not quite getting why he thought that was so
funny. He laughed to himself for a good 30 seconds. “Anyway, Auggie, thanks for
chatting with me,” he said, finally. “I just want you to know it’s truly a pleasure
having you here at beater Prep, and I’m really looking forward to next year.” He
reached across the desk and we shook hands. “See you tomorrow at
graduation.” “See you tomorrow, Mr.
Tushman the last precept THIS WAS WRITTEN on Mr Brown's chalkboard when we walked into English
class for the last time: MR Brown's JUNE PRECEPT: JUST FOLLOW THE DAY AND REACH
FOR THE SUN! (The Polyphonic Spree) Have a great summer vacation, Class 5B it's It’s
been a great year and you’ve been a wonderful group of students If you
remember, please send me a postcard this summer with YOUR personal precept. It can
be something you made up for yourself or something you’ve read somewhere that
means something to you. (If so, don’t forget the attribution, please!) I really
look forward to getting them Tom Brown 563 Sebastian Place Bronx New York
100053 thanks thanks for watching don't forget to like And subscribe become a
channel member and we'll see you in the next video